{
  "title": "PBL of Nutrition",
  "questions": [
    {
      "stem": "Which of the following features is constant feature of KWO?",
      "options": [
        "hepatomegaly",
        "hair changes",
        "edema",
        "skin changes"
      ],
      "correct": 2
    },
    {
      "stem": "The most common form of under nutrition is:",
      "options": [
        "marasmus",
        "Kwo",
        "wasting",
        "Stunting"
      ],
      "correct": 3
    },
    {
      "stem": "From variable features of",
      "options": [
        "edema.",
        "skin changes.",
        "Apathy",
        "Failure of growth"
      ],
      "correct": 1
    },
    {
      "stem": "The daily caloric requirement of marasmis infant?",
      "options": [
        "50 cal/kg/day",
        "100 cal/kg/day",
        "150 cal/kg/day",
        "75 cal/kg/day"
      ],
      "correct": 2
    },
    {
      "stem": "You are in the clinic and a mother comes worried about her milk supply and wants to add formula feeding, the baby is a 5-day- old full term newborn with a birth weight of 3.5 kg and now he has the same weight. He wets 8 diapers and does 3 times stools per day. What would you tell her?",
      "options": [
        "Switch to formula feeding.",
        "Your baby needs special formula.",
        "Your breast feeding is adequate.",
        "You need to add formula."
      ],
      "correct": 2
    },
    {
      "stem": "The following is TRUE about breast milk:",
      "options": [
        "Colostrum has a lower protein content than breast milk.",
        "Colostrum is produced within 2 to 3 weeks.",
        "Mature breast milk has a higher mineral content.",
        "Mature breast milk is usually thinner in consistency than colostrum."
      ],
      "correct": 3
    },
    {
      "stem": "You are in charge of 1.3-kilogram- preterm baby in the NICU and you decide to give him formula. Why do you better pick the preterm ?",
      "options": [
        "It has higher lactose content than term formula.",
        "It has higher protein content than term formula.",
        "It has lower calorie content than mature formula.",
        "Lipids are in the form of long chain fatty acids"
      ],
      "correct": 1
    },
    {
      "stem": "To ensure successful breast feeding, what would be a correct advice to give to the mother?",
      "options": [
        "Avoid skin to skin contact with the newborn baby.",
        "Start giving oral glucose immediately after delivery.",
        "Start pacifier use immediately after delivery.",
        "Try to establish early breast feeding."
      ],
      "correct": 3
    },
    {
      "stem": "On the 1st day of life, which of the following supplemental vitamins should be administrated to a term newborn, regardless of future plans to breastfeed or offer formula?",
      "options": [
        "Iron.",
        "Vitamin D.",
        "Vitamin E.",
        "Vitamin K."
      ],
      "correct": 1
    },
    {
      "stem": "What is the number of calories present in mature breast milk ?",
      "options": [
        "100 kcal/dl.",
        "90 kcal/dl",
        "81 kcal/dl.",
        "67 kcal/dl."
      ],
      "correct": 3
    },
    {
      "stem": "A mother brings her 3-week- old female baby born 2.4-kg-weight complaining of abdominal distension, vomiting and continuous crying. On examination, the baby looks healthy, well hydrated, passing stools, a current weight of 5 kg and distended abdomen. What is your MOST LIKELY diagnosis?",
      "options": [
        "Duodenal atresia.",
        "Neonatal sepsis.",
        "Over-feeding.",
        "Pyloric stenosis."
      ],
      "correct": 2
    },
    {
      "stem": "A mother brings her 6-month-old boy for a well-child visit. Which of the following is TRUE about weaning her baby?",
      "options": [
        "Add salt to food for a better food acceptance.",
        "Avoid high risk choking foods.",
        "Fresh juice is mandatory.",
        "Start by cow's milk derivatives."
      ],
      "correct": 1
    },
    {
      "stem": "To ensure successful breast feeding, what would be correct advice to give to the mother?",
      "options": [
        "Avoid skin to skin contact with the newborn baby",
        "Start giving oral glucose immediately after delivery",
        "Start pacifier use immediately after delivery",
        "Try to establish early breast feeding"
      ],
      "correct": 3
    },
    {
      "stem": "Hyper vitaminosis D is manifested by the following except",
      "options": [
        "constipation.",
        "renal stones",
        "convulsions",
        "polyuria"
      ],
      "correct": 2
    }
  ]
}
